PROFILE

An experienced medical officer adept in the provision of evidencebased healthcare services in all disciplines of medicine and surgery with partial interests in global health: healthcare policy in Africa and healthcare management. The combination of clinical practice, public health and management skills makes me an excellent problem-solver and a key player in a relevant progressive environment. I have particular interests in preventative care, endocrinology, nephrology and volunteerism.

ADDRESS

156 AKO LP GD-052-6966

GD-052-7265 GhanaPost

CONTACT

PHONE:

+233557613434

WEBSITE:

www.drampofo.com

BLOGSITE:

www.drampofo.wordpress.com

EMAIL:

Abenakonadu95@gmail.com

DR. AUGUSTINA KONADU LARBI-AMPOFO

MEDICAL OFFICER

EDUCATION

University of Suffolk

June 2020 – November 2022

Masters in Science in Public Health: Health Policy

University of Ghana School of Medicine and Dentistry

September 2013 – September 2019

Bachelor of Medicine and Surgery (MBCHB)

Bachelor of Science in Medical Sciences (BSc.)

Achimota Senior High School

2010 to 2013

High School Diploma

WORK EXPERIENCE

HealthNet Airport Medical Center

- Medical Officer
- Business Development Officer
- Health blogger

June 2022-Present

As the clinical personnel of the business development unit, I contribute to the creation of enabling environment for impeccable service provision and organizational growth via marketing through the internet and social media

Gilead Medical and Dental Center [Medical Officer]

October 2022-Present, Part-time

As a medical officer, I manage common health-related conditions and refer appropriately for urgent and specialist care.

Princess Marie Louise Hospital [Paediatric Intern]

December 2021-May 2022

Upper West Regional Hospital [Surgery Intern]

June 2021 - November 2021

Tamale Teaching Hospital

- Internal Medicine and Obstetrics and Gynaecology Intern
- Research Assistant

April 2020 – May 2021

Under supervision, I provided medical, obstetrics and gynaecology, trauma, surgical, emergency and paediatric care while rotating through these departments.

LANGUAGES

- English (official language)
- French (intermediate)

SOCIAL PROJECTS

- UN volunteer
- Proffer-Aid International Foundation, since 2019

Centered on women health promotion activities, I engage in radio and social-media talks/ discussions on cervical and breast cancers

- Operation Serve, since 2019
- 'Where there are no doctors', I participate in health screening activities and training programs on first aid and basic medical care in the remotest parts of Ghana
- Hilton Foundation
 International, since 2022
 I function as a mental health
 advocate. I organize conferences
 on the psychosocial issues among
 abandoned children. Serving as the
 health arm of the organization, I
 organize general medical and
 dental health screening services
 among carers and children of
 orphanages.

Functioning as a research assistant, I collected, collated and analyzed primary data for my department in their research activities

SKILLS

Clinical skills:

- BLS/ACLS

- Interpretation of ECG reports

- Focused Assessment Sonography in Trauma

- Chest tube placement and removal

- Fracture reduction and splinting

- Wound suturing

- Incision and drainage

- Manual evacuation of the uterus

Non-Clinical Skills:

- Radio Hosting
- Blogging
- Telemedicine
- Healthcare marketing
- Social media promotion
- Proficient in research
- Program Organization
- Team player

ACADEMIC CERTIFICATIONS

Mental Health diplomaAlison Empower YourselfMarch, 2023Marketing through the internet and social mediaAlison Empower YourselfMarch, 2023Tele-health for healthcare providersAlison Empower YourselfMarch, 2023Basic life support clinical training workshopGhana Medical HelpMay, 2022Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentialityMedical and Surgical Skills Institute (MSSI, Ghana)December, 2022Advanced Cardiac Life SupportAfrica Partners Medical, GhanaJuly, 2021Leadership and Management in HealthUniversity of WashingtonJune, 2021Covid-19 training module for all health workersContinuous Education Services, GhanaAugust, 2020Abortion: the legal framework- what to known to avoid jailContinuous Education Services, GhanaAugust, 2020	CERTIFICATE	AWARDING BODY	DATE
Marketing through the internet and social media Tele-health for healthcare providers Basic life support clinical training workshop Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentiality Alison Empower Yourself Alison Empower Yourself March, 2023 March, 2022 March, 2023 March, 2022 March, 2022 March, 2023 May, 2022 May, 2022 The providers Africa Partners Medical, Ghana Leadership and Management in Health Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Continuous Education Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020	Mental Health diploma	Alison Empower	March,
Tele-health for healthcare providers Basic life support clinical training workshop Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentiality Advanced Cardiac Life Support Leadership and Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Alison Empower Yourself Alison Empower Yourself March, 2023 March, 2023 March, 2023 Many, 2022 Many, 2022 Many, 2022 Many, 2022 December, 2022 July, 2021 July, 2021 June, 2021 August, 2020 August, 2020	_	Yourself	2023
Tele-health for healthcare providers Basic life support clinical training workshop Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentiality Advanced Cardiac Life Support Leadership and Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Alison Empower Yourself March, 2023 March, 2023 March, 2023 May, 2022 May, 2022 Medical and Surgical Skills Institute (MSSI, Ghana) December, 2022 July, 2021 June, 2021 August, 2020 August, 2020	Marketing through the	Alison Empower	March,
healthcare providers Yourself Yourself Zo23 Basic life support clinical training workshop Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentiality Advanced Cardiac Life Support Leadership and Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Medical Medical Help May, 2022 Medical and Surgical Skills Institute (MSSI, 2022 Medical Partners Medical, Ghana July, 2021 June, 2021 August, 2020	internet and social media	Yourself	2023
Basic life support clinical training workshop Medical Law and Ethics: Patient confidentiality Advanced Cardiac Life Support Leadership and Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Ghana Medical Help May, 2022 Medical and Surgical Skills Institute (MSSI, 2022 Medical Partners Medical, Ghana July, 2021 June, 2021 August, 2020 August, 2020	Tele-health for	Alison Empower	March,
training workshopMedical and Surgical Skills Institute (MSSI, Ghana)December, 2022Advanced Cardiac Life SupportAfrica Partners Medical, GhanaJuly, 2021Leadership and Management in HealthUniversity of WashingtonJune, 2021Covid-19 training module for all health workersContinuous Education Services, GhanaAugust, 2020Abortion: the legal framework- what toContinuous Education Services, GhanaAugust, 2020	healthcare providers	Yourself	2023
Patient confidentiality Skills Institute (MSSI, Ghana) Advanced Cardiac Life Support Africa Partners Medical, Ghana Leadership and University of Washington Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Skills Institute (MSSI, 2022 Africa Partners Medical, Ghana July, 2021 June, 2021 Continuous Education August, 2020 August, 2020		Ghana Medical Help	May, 2022
Advanced Cardiac Life Support Africa Partners Medical, Ghana Leadership and Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Ghana Africa Partners Medical, Ghana July, 2021 June, 2021 August, 2020 August, Services, Ghana Continuous Education Services, Ghana August, 2020	Medical Law and Ethics:	Medical and Surgical	December,
Support Medical, Ghana University of Washington Covid-19 training module for all health workers Abortion: the legal framework- what to Medical, Ghana University of Washington June, 2021 August, 2020 August, 2020	Patient confidentiality	,	2022
Leadership and Management in Health University of Washington June, 2021 Covid-19 training Continuous Education Services, Ghana Services, Ghana Continuous Education Services, Ghana Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020 Abortion: the legal Framework- what to Services, Ghana Continuous Education Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020	Advanced Cardiac Life	Africa Partners	July, 2021
Management in Health Covid-19 training module for all health workers Continuous Education Services, Ghana Continuous Education Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020 Abortion: the legal framework- what to Services, Ghana Continuous Education Services, Ghana	Support	Medical, Ghana	
Covid-19 training module for all health workers Continuous Education Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020 Continuous Education August, Services, Ghana Continuous Education August, 2020	Leadership and	University of	June, 2021
module for all health workers Services, Ghana 2020 Abortion: the legal framework- what to Services, Ghana 2020 August, 2020	Management in Health	Washington	
workers Abortion: the legal Continuous Education August, framework- what to Services, Ghana 2020			<u> </u>
framework- what to Services, Ghana 2020		Services, Ghana	2020
, , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , ,	Abortion: the legal	Continuous Education	August,
known to avoid jail	framework- what to	Services, Ghana	2020
<u> </u>	known to avoid jail		